不知道它们从哪跑出来的  你得帮我们
Came out of nowhere. You gotta help us.
你看这些脏水
Look at all this damn water.
千万别喝
Don't drink that.
说不定是有毒的
Ain't no telling what's gonna be poison.
第四季 第七集
S04E07: Problem Dog
儿子怎么样了
How's Junior?
和我预计的一样
Oh, exactly what I expected.
自从我们说要退掉车之后
He hasn't said a word to me
他一句话都没和我说过
since we told him it was going back.
我和车行谈过了  他们不同意退车
I spoke to the dealership. They didn't want to take it.
什么
What?
这车的车况这么好
It's in perfect condition.
而且只跑了17英里
It's got 17 miles on the odometer.
我知道  我说了一个小时的好话
I know. I spent the better part of an hour
才让经理把退订费降到
sweet-talking the manager down to a restocking fee--
800块
$800.
才2天就要800块
$800... for two days?
根据法律来说  他们有权利拒绝退车
Well, the law says they don't have to take it back at all.
好了  这是登记表
All right, here's the registration,
标签还有收据
and the window sticker, the receipt.
记得一定要找那个总经理
Oh, and make sure you talk to the general manager.
他叫格伦
His name is Glen.
格伦
Glen.
有什么事就打给我
Call me if there's a problem.
还有拜托你
And please, just don't--
不要和任何人争执
don't tangle with anyone.
好吧
Fine.
很好  马丁  非常好
Oh! Bueno, Martine. Muy bueno.
沃尔特
Walt.
妈的
Shit.
喂  你好
Yes. Hello.
我需要一辆出租车
I need a cab.
对  谢谢  我叫怀特
Yes, thank you. The name is White.
我在大学城的展览馆停车场
Uh, I'm at the Pavilion parking lot on University.
对  没错  就在机场南边
Oh, yes, that's right. Just south of the airport.
太好了  谢谢
Oh, that'd be great. Thank you.
大概多久能到
Oh, how long do you think that would take.
不用  他肯定能找到我的
No, I'm sure he'll see me.
谢谢
Thank you.
有没有悔过
Contrition?
当然有
Hey, there's--
彻底的悔过
There's total contrition here!
简直后悔死了
There's mountains of contrition!
太  太好了
Fan-tan-tastic!
我现在就把钱送过去
I will messenger 'em over right away.
还有
Oh, and--
关于那件事
...about that other thing unrelated--
我可以让你加入
Yes, I can get you in.
但我得警告你  第八洞简直不是人打的
But I gotta warn you, the eighth hole is murder.
是吗  你就想来点刺激的
Oh, yeah? You want to make it interesting?
太棒了  早上7点准时开球
Great! Tee time 7 A.M. Sharp.
准备输得屁滚尿流吧你
Prepare to have your ass handed to you.
好的  再见
Okay. Bye.
他本来要告你毁坏公物
He was headed for destruction of property,
但既然那车是你的
but since it's your own property,
我让他改成轻罪  乱烧垃圾
I sweated him down to misdemeanor trash burning.
唯一的问题就是要花不少钱
The only thing is, it's not gonna be free.
罚金5000块
There's a 5 grand fine,
拖车和清理现场600块
600 for towing and disposal,
蒸汽清洗柏油路3000块
another 3 grand to steam clean the blacktop.
所以你这小小的飙车之旅要花掉你
So bottom line, your little joyride's gonna set you back
大概52000块
about 52,000 bucks, so...
你觉得值吗
was it worth it?
我不想听这些废话
I don't need to hear the blow-by-blow.
直接告诉我问题解决了
Just tell me it's done.
不好意思  我吵醒你了吗
I'm sorry, did I wake you?
我在这事闹大之前就帮你摆平了
I caught this thing before it got into the system.
所以你不会有案底
That means your record stays clean.
你老婆也永远不会发现
The wife never finds out.
这是见证奇迹的时刻
I've been working magic here.
至少夸我一下吧
I can at least get an "Attaboy."
好吧  你自己生闷气去吧
Fine. Rebel without a cause,
袋子给我
give.
到底什么事  关于福林吗
What is it, Fring?
他会干掉我
He will see me dead...
我却束手无策
and there's nothing I can do about it.
只能坐以待毙
All that's left is to wait.
你确定吗
And we're sure about this.
平克曼说他很需要你
'Cause Pinkman says he needs you too much.
"平克曼说"
"Pinkman says."
除非
Unless...
你能给我找个帮手
you could help me find a third party.
什么帮手
What third party?
能帮我改善情势的人
Someone who can ameliorate the situation.
说得明白点行不行
Let's ditch the thesaurus, all right?
你是想找个杀手吗
You talking about a hit man?
如果他们还叫这名字的话
Assuming that's still what they're called.
回答错误
Zzzzt! Wrong answer!
用年轻的人话来说就是扯淡
That's what the kids call "Epic fail."
你只要给我一个号码
All I would need is a phone number.
剩下的我来做就行
I would do the rest.
索尔  我会付你钱的
Saul, there'd be a finder's fee.
一大笔钱
A big one.
如果你一定要的话
Look, if you held my feet to the fire,
我可以帮你找一两个西洛基山的人
I could come up with a couple names one or two guys west of the Rockies
帮你做这事
who do this kind of work
但你知道吗
but guess what.
这些人  他们都认识麦克
These guys? They know Mike.
麦克也认识他们
And Mike knows them.
你是说
What are you telling me?
麦克认识所有干这行的人
Mike knows everyone who does this?
你以为是谁介绍他们给我的
Who do you think gave me their names?
好吧  备选方案
Okay, Plan B.
不找我认识的人
Look, we go outside my network--
从广告或者佣兵
Craigslist, Soldier of Fortune.
就算我们运气好
Let's say we get lucky,
超级超级好
I mean, incredibly lucky,
找到一个既不是卧底警察
and find a guy who's not an undercover cop
也不是疯子的人
or some kind of survivalist nut-job wannabe.
你得问问自己  到底怎样才算好
You gotta ask yourself-- How good is good enough?
不管我们找到什么人
Because whatever goomba we buy
到最后那人都会遇上我们的朋友
at some point is gonna come head-to-head
麦克
with our friend Mike.
至于  古斯・福林
And Gus Fring?
干掉他
Just winging that guy
根本不会"改善你的情势"
is not gonna ameliorate your situation,
一点也不会
not by a damn sight.
我想自己解决  但我根本见不到他
I tried to slove this myself, but I can't get anywhere near him.
你见不到他
You can't get near him?
去问问你的搭档吧
Why don't you ask your partner?
是  我见过他
Yeah, I saw him.
你告诉索尔都不告诉我
And you tell Saul before you tell me?
他也是我律师  和你一样
Look, he's my lawyer, same as yours.
每次我过去
Every time I go over there,
他都要和问我麦克的事
Saul hassles me about Mike.
他还在害怕有一天他会过去打断他的腿
He's still scared the dude's gonna come break his legs.
所以这些事我都告诉他
So I give him the latest.
到底怎么回事
But what happened exactly?
我在和麦克吃晚餐
I was at a diner with Mike,
他突然出现
and he just shows up.
他们让我出去  然后自己在里面谈
They send me outside and the two of them talk.
就这样
That's it.
这是他们定期的见面吗
So this is like a regular thing?
你离他有多近
How close were you to him?
很近
Close.
比咱俩现在这样还近
Closer than you and me right now.
他和你说话了么
Did he speak to you?
只说了不到10秒
It was over in 10 seconds.
回答我的问题
Would you just answer?
他说他看人很准
He said he sees things in people.
什么事  看什么人
What things? What people?
看我
Me.
他说他能看到我的潜力
He said he sees something in me.
一个月前
A month ago,
古斯还想杀了咱俩
Gus was trying to kill both of us,
现在他把你调出实验室
and now he pulls you out of the lab
然后把你当做好像
and employs you as...
好像  二号枪手
what, an assistant gunman?
还是硬汉人物
A tough guy?
你不觉得很奇怪吗
Does that make any sense to you?
他说他能看到你的潜力
He says he sees something in you.
他到底在玩什么把戏
What kind of game is he playing?
以为你真的那么天真吗
Does he think you're that naive?
他不会真的相信你已经忘了
He can't truly think that you'd forget--
好吧  撇开盖尔不谈
Well, let alone Gale,
也不说维克托
let alone Victor,
也别谈那些随之而来的可怕经历
and all the horror that goes along with all of that.
你的女朋友
What about this girlfriend of yours
还有她的那位小弟弟呢
and her little brother?
那男人看着你的眼睛
The man looked you straight in the eye
对你说  不会再用小孩子了
and told you "No more children,"
可就在那晚  那小男孩
but that very night, that little boy...
就这么死了
he winds up...
古斯不会真认为你忘了那些了吧
Gus can't possibly think that you'd forget that.
-行了  -我说这些是为了证明
- Okay. - I mean, all I'm saying is that
他不会真的以为你的意志那么薄弱吧
is it possible he would think that you're that weak-willed?
别摆出那副宣传的强调
Drop the sales pitch.
我会做的
I'll do it.
那你会做什么
You'll do what?
我会杀了他的
I'll kill him...
只要一有机会就会下手
First chance I'll get.
菠萝香味  闻起来更像变质的泡泡糖
Pina colada? More like stale bubblegum.
真有人希望他们的车闻起来
Does anyone actually want their car to smell like
像一个六年级孩子的课桌
the bottom of a sixth-grader's desk?
好吧  大麻味  不会吧
Okay. Hemp? Really?
我知道  可你知道那句话
Yeah, I know. But you know what they say--
顾客永远是对的
the customer's always right.
说到顾客
Ooh! Speaking of customer,
现在开一个盛大的开业仪式还来得及
it's not too late to have a grand opening.
举办一个大型派对  到处都是气球
I was thinking huge party, balloons,
还有孩子玩的蹦蹦床
bouncy house for the kids,
引起轰动  顺便上个电视
you know, make a splash, get on TV.
让人们知道他们进来后
Let people know they're not gonna have to face
不会遭遇冷颜相对
the eyebrows of doom when they come in.
玛丽  汉克最近怎样
Marie, how's Hank doing?
你猜怎么着  他比以前好多了
You know what? He's doing better.
真的吗
Really?
没错
Yeah. Uh...
最近他的心情大好
Lately his mood's improved,
他像疯了一样做那些物理治疗
and he's like a maniac with his P.T.
-那太好了  -是的  不过别理解错了
- That's fantastic. - Yeah, don't get me wrong.
他离完全恢复还差很远  可他
He's got a long way to go, but he--
我懂  我是说
Yeah. I mean--
-你好啊  沃尔特  -玛丽
- Hi, Walt. - Marie.
-见到你真好  -见到你也一样
- It's good to see you. - You, too.
你的这个收银员可是能说会道
Hey, your cashier here is quite the salesperson.
她刚说的我对车子的
She just talked me into something called
全身上蜡感兴趣了
the Orbital Paste Wax Buff.
当然  对汽车外漆的保养可是很重要的
Oh, yeah. No, it's very important to maintain your clear coat.
要是一旦保护层没了
Boy, once that goes--
的确
Oh, yeah.
博格丹时期高峰时段平均每小时19辆车
Bogdan was averaging 19 cars during rush hour,
而现在我们已经提高到22辆
and we are already up to 22--
22辆车
22 actual cars.
昨晚  我们挣了3800美元
Lat night, I depoted $3,800.
上帝  这里有多少钱
Jesus. How much is that?
27万4千美元
$274,000.
应该有些误差
Give or take.
-有误差  -没错
- Give or take? - Yeah.
我没准确数过
I haven't counted it.
等等
Wait...
27万4千美元  多久一次
274,000-- And this is how often?
每两个礼拜
Every two weeks.
礼拜四方便来放钱吗
Thursday's good for a drop-off?
等等  沃尔特
Wait, Walt.
难道你是在说
Are you telling me
一年能挣七百一十二万美元
you make $7,125,000 a year?
应该是七百五十万
7 1/2 even,
在开销之前
before expenses.
可我不能
But I can't--
这太多了
This is too much.
看来是比你想象的多
So it's more than you thought,
是个坏消息喽
and this is somehow bad news?
不  重点不是这个
No, that's not the point.
我是说  世界上没有哪一个洗车房
I mean, there is no car wash in the world
能做这样的生意
that could do this kind of business.
这需要最少九个月的工作
I mean, this is 9 month's work here minimum.
能赚7百万  那起码得好几年
7 million? That could take years.
那就存着一些  以备不时之需
So set some aside. Save it for a rainy day.
存着  你说什么
Save it. What--
存到哪里  我又不能去银行存
Save it where? I can't go to the bank with it.
也不能保存在这里
I sure can't leave it here.
等等  都是50美元大钞
Wait a minute. Is this all 50s?
谁洗车付50美元
Who pays for a car wash with a 50?
斯凯勒  我没有要求你这么做
Skyler, I didn't ask you to do this.
我原以为
I was under the impression
你能控制大局
that you had this under control.
可我没想到这么多钱
I just didn't expect this amount of money.
50美元大钞会是个问题
The 50s are gonna be a problem.
好吧  那就开始解决问题吧
Well, that's what this is-- problem solving.
斯凯勒  我们分工很明确
Skyler, this is a simple division of labor.
我赚钱  你洗钱
I bring in the money, you launder the money.
是你想这么做的
This is what you wanted.
我从来没想做这些
I never wanted any of this.
我得走了
I've got to go.
要是你想退出  就说出来
If you want out, just say that you want out.
这不结了
Okay, then.
你是说你在实验室做的这个
You're telling me you made this in the lab?
怎么不行
Why not?
在他自己的实验室里制作
Making it in his own lab...
合情合理
seemed appropriate.
量不多啊
There's not much of it.
对付屠库用的比这多
We had more for Tuco.
这些足够了
It's enough.
这还是最妙的办法
This is still the best way.
你提着枪去杀他
You go after him with a gun,
根本不可能活着回来
you'll never get out of it alive.
但是有了这个
But with this,
你只要把这个倒进他的食物或者饮料中
you slip it into his food or drink,
完全无色无味
there shouldn't be any taste or smell,
36小时后  死翘翘
36 hours later, poof.
一个男的  到了这个年纪
A man his age,
又这般卖命工作
working as hard as he does,
没人会感到奇怪
no one will be surprised.
麦克怎么办
What about Mike?
麦克会起疑心
Mike can have his suspicions,
但也只是起疑心而已
but that's all they'll be.
一个一个来
Please, one homicidal maniac at a time.
我不知道什么时候才能再见到古斯
I don't know when I'm gonna see Gus again...
能不能再见到都难说
I mean, if ever.
随身带着
Keep it with you.
一旦有机会
When you have the opportunity,
你就要做好准备
be ready.
他们搜我身怎么办
What if they search me?
他们会吗
Will they do that?
这根放反了
It's the wrong way around.
这是我的幸运香烟
It's my lucky cigarette.
随你便吧  只是别抽这一根
Well, whatever you do, don't smoke it.
你知道他们是有得来速通道的吧
You know they have a drive-thru, right?
不  没关系
Nah, this is good.
要多锻炼  促进血液循环
Could use the exercise. Get he blood pumping.
别担心
Don't worry,
你不用来接我了
you're not gonna have to pick me up.
虽然要费点时间  可我还是能到那里的
It might take me a while, but I'll get there.
天啊  我们俩简直是一对了
Jesus, ain't we a pair?
看来你是真心喜欢吃炸鸡啊
You must really like chicken.
V8引擎  470马力
V-8, 470 horses,
20英寸轮毂
20-inch rims,
卫星广播  车载蓝牙
satellite radio, Bluetooth,
百公里加速只要4.7秒
0 to 60 in 4.7 seconds.
哇  你不是在说笑吧
Whoa. What do you mean, on a lark?
突然之间  你爸爸灵光一现
Spur of the moment, your dad just ups and buys you
给你买了一辆全新的道奇挑战者?
a brand-new Challenger?
是啊  我刚开过街角
Yeah, I barely got around the block
我妈就说我们家供不起
and Mom said we couldn't afford it,
于是就把车收回去了
so they took it back.
知道我一共玩了多久吗
Do you know how long I had it?
15小时
Fifteen hours.
好吧  伙计  我跟你说
Well, hey, buddy, let me tell you something.
我在你那个年龄的时候
When I was your age,
要是能让我开那种车
I'd have given my left nut
我愿意割掉左边的蛋  哪怕只有15分钟
to drive a car like that for 15 minutes.
说真的  怎么会有这种事呢
But seriously, how does that happen?
我们当时在看二手车
Well, we were looking at used cars,
我就有点...
and I kind of...
你搞得你家老头内疚了
You guilted him into it.
是啊是啊  我懂了
Yeah, yeah. I know. I hear you.
你又开始谈自己多可怜  还有点小毛病
You pulled the old "Poor little me and my little troubles."
-是不是  -差不多吧
- Am I right? - Maybe.
飞近了太阳  翅膀可是会融化的  小伙子
Yeah, well, you flew too close to the sun, my friend.
要是他给你买的是一辆破车
You'd have let him buy you a clunker
你现在就能开着它了
you'd be driving now,
不用开你妈的老破车了
instead of borrowing Mom's hooptie.
施拉德探员
Agent Schrader.
-你好吗  -很好  多谢关心
- Oh, hey. How you doing? - Well, thank you.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
小沃尔特  还记得福林先生吗
Walter Junior, do you remember Mr. Fring?
-您好吗  -很高兴再次见到你
- How are you? Well. - Nice to see you again.
你们能光临这里是我们的荣幸
It's a pleasure to see you here.
您看起来气色不错
You're looking very well.
是啊  你知道的
Yeah, well, you know,
全靠维生素片过活了
chalk it up to clean living and vitamin pills.
真抱歉
I must apologize.
要是看见您进门
If I had seen you come in,
绝对不会收您钱的
there would have been no question of accepting your money.
今后  您一定记得要叫我
In the future, please feel free to ask for me.
在我们洛博罗炸鸡馆
A DEA hero should never have
一位缉毒局英雄是绝对应该免费用餐的
to pay for a meal at Pollos Hermanos.
真的吗
No kidding?
你这话我可记下了
I'll take you up on that for sure.
你父母怎样了
And how are your mother and father?
他们很好
They're good.
炸鸡真不错
The chicken is great.
谢谢
Thank you.
要是想做一些零工赚点零花钱
If ever you're interested in rewarding part-time work,
比如放学后打打零工
perhaps something after school?
尽管来找我
My door is always open.
听着不错
Sounds good.
这听着不妙啊
Uh, I don't know about this one.
他可能吃到你们店亏本
He might eat up all your profits.
不打扰您二位用餐了
Well, I'll let you finish your meal.
还要点什么吗
Can I get you anything else?
续杯吗
A refill, perhaps?
不用  我够了
No, thank you. I'm good.
我要  来一杯健怡可乐  谢谢
Sure. Take a Diet Coke. Thank you very much.
没问题
Of course.
我们去哪儿
So where are we going?
今天可有重要任务要干
Oh, big doings today.
今天给你的任务是  睁大眼睛  闭紧嘴巴
The order of the day is eyes open, mouth shut.
你好吗
S'up?
试音  试音
Test, test.
听到吗
You got me?
报数
Count off.
我们走
Let's go.
就这里  请把包装留着
Right here. Leave the wrap on, please.
会做咖啡吗
You know how to make coffee?
当然了
Sure.
去做吧
There you go.
-我简单汇报一下  -请说
- You want a rundown? - Please.
大门处有三个人
Three guys up at the gate--
两个在明处  一个在暗处
two visible, one in the blind.
这里有五个隐蔽起来的后援
We got five guys down here with a backup out of sight.
我让泰鲁斯带着巴雷特狙击步枪
I got Tyrus down in the treeline
埋伏在树丛后面
with a Barret .50.
昨晚就让他潜伏下来
Planted him there last night
防止对手提前打埋伏
in case we had any early arrivals.
我没有多余的枪套了
I don't have an extra holster.
把这个放在你的口袋里  别给人看见
You stick this in your pocket. Keep it out of sight.
如果你今天要呆在这里的话  就得拿把枪
If you're gonna be here today, you're gonna have a gun.
子弹上膛了吗
It's loaded?
我没拔枪的话
I don't want to see that in your hand
你就不要拿枪
unless you see me with mine.
明白了吗
Understood?
只是应急用的
Emergency only.
第一辆车来了
First car is coming.
好  今天你的任务是什么
All right, what's the order of the day?
睁大眼睛  闭紧嘴巴
Eyes open, mouth shut.
好多枪啊
A lot of guns.
没人让你放下武器
Nobody's asking you to give up yours.
你难道想在你们的人来之前把这里扫荡一遍
You want to sweep the place before you bring in your guys?
我就是那个人
I am the guy.
那好吧
All right, then.
欢迎
和你一起来的人呢
来的只有我而已
为什么
老板相信我能充分捍卫他们的利益
请坐
以下是我提的条件
考虑到我们之前的良好关系
我打算一次性付5500万美元
这段恩怨就此了断了
我不会另外付钱  我们从此中断联系
彻底了断
你没有什么回复吗
以下是我的回复
是  还是否
你很清楚我们集团要的是什么
说别的什么都是浪费时间
是  还是否
谈判刚开始就这么僵持
这个问题不容谈判
你那儿是不是还有我的东西
You got something of mine?
放杂物箱里
Glove box.
我想还是要教你怎么开枪
Figure I better teach you how to shoot.
局面可能会很棘手
Could be things are gonna get hairy.
这什么意思
What is this?
你会给我配把枪
You're giving me a gun?
我现在是组织的一员了吗
And now I'm, like, part of the team or whatever?
他说我身上有种特质
He said he sees something in me.
是什么
Like what?
如果简而言之的话
If I had to put it in a word...
我猜想
I'd guess...
是忠诚
loyalty.
忠诚
Loyalty.
是啊
Yeah.
也许只是效忠错了人
Only maybe you got it for the wrong guy.
杰西
Jesse?
好久不见
Long time, no see.
近来好吗
How you doing?
还行
Yeah, you know, uh...
挺好
good.
那就好
Good.
我们要开始了
Okay, we're going to get started.
你进来吗
You coming in?
实际上  我们无法改变过去
So the truth is we can't change the past.
事实既定
What's done is done.
我们要为自己的行为负责
We've got to own our actions,
但是给自己量刑定罪
but putting ourselves on trial,
充当自己的法官  陪审团  和行刑员
acting as our own judge, jury, and executioner,
并不是解决之道
it's not the answer
因为很多时候  这种审判
because a lot of the time all that judging does
只会让我们重蹈覆辙
is just ensure that we're going to repeat the cycle.
对吧
Right.
"我真是个混蛋"
"I'm such an asshole."
"没救了"
"It's totally hopeless."
"有何意义"
"What's the point?"
"我想我要再吸一次"
"I think I'll have a hit."
杰西
Jesse.
你的近况如何
What's going on with you these days?
我复吸了
I went back to the crystal.
那你现在清醒么
You sober now?
是啊
Yeah.
四天了  很难得  对吧
Four days. Big whoop, right?
四天也是进步
Four days is four days.
你能来就很好
You're here.
你还在洗衣店工作吗
You still... working at the laundry?
那里怎样
How are things there.
逊毙了
Sucks ass.
你想聊聊吗
Anything you want to talk about?
几周前
a couple of weeks back...
我
I, uh...
杀了一条狗
killed a dog.
你的车撞了它么
You hit it with your car?
不是
No, um...
我亲手杀了他
I put him down.
我看着他死去
I watched him go.
我直视他的双眼
I was looking him straight in the eye and...
他不清楚是怎么回事
you know, he didn't know what was happening.
他不知道原因
He didn't know why. He--
他只是害怕  然后
He was just scared, and then...
死了
he was gone.
他活着很煎熬
He was suffering.
替他了结算是种善举
It was a kindness.
不  他没生病
No, he wasn't sick.
不  他只是
No, he was just, like a...
我说不清  就像只
I don't know, like a...
不正常的狗
problem dog.
他做了什么
What did he do?
咬人了吗
Bite someone?
这只狗从不咬人
Uh, this dog never-- never bit anybody.
他是...
He was, uh...
你吸毒了  失去理智
You pick up the rock, you go right to the dark side.
什么都可能发生
Anything can happen.
我不是因为吸了毒
It ain't no rock that made me do it.
那是什么问题
Well, what was the problem?
你为什么非得杀了他
Why did you have to kill him?
请注意交流的语气
Watch the cross-talk, please.
也许细节并不重要
Maybe it's not the details that matter.
对吧
Right?
你对你的行为怎么想  杰西
How'd you feel about what you did, Jesse?
我不知道
I don't know.
谁管你怎么想
Who cares how you feel?
什么样的人  会无缘无故残杀一只狗
What kind of a person kills a dog for no reason?
科琳
Colleen.
你可以登报征养
You put an ad in the paper.
-你可以把他送到收容所  -科琳
- You drop him off at a shelter. - Colleen--
你就是不能端坐在这儿
You just don't sit there
说自己杀了一只无助的
and talk about killing a helpless--
-科琳  -无辜的动物
- Colleen. - ...innocent animal.
我们来这儿不是为了评判别人
We're not here to sit in judgment.
有何不可
Why not?
有何不可  也许她是对的
Why not? Maybe-- Maybe she's right.
也许我该登报
You know, maybe I should have put it in the paper.
也许我当时该做点别的
Maybe I should have done something different.
重点是
The thing is,
如果瞻前顾后  规规矩矩
if you just do stuff and nothing happens...
那还有什么意思
what's it all mean?
有何意义
What's the point?
这个讨论是关于自我接受
All right, this whole thing is about self-acceptance.
否定自己
Kicking the hell out of yourself
并无益处
doesn't give meaning to anything.
那我就该停止评判
So I should stop judging...
-全盘接受  -这只是开始
- and accept... - It's a start.
无论我做什么
So, no matter what I do,
都该为我欢呼  因为我是个好人吗
hooray for me because I'm a great guy?
这样对吗
It's all good?
无论我杀了多少条狗
No matter how many dogs I kill,
我就记录一下  然后淡然接受吗
I just what, do an inventory and accept?
你倒车压死了自己的孩子
I mean, you back your truck over your own kid
你就这么接受了吗
and you, like, accept?
这简直是废话
What a load of crap!
杰西  我知道你很痛苦
Hey, Jesse, I know you're in pain.
不  你知道吗
No, y-you know what?
我当初为什么来这儿
Why I'm here in the first place?
是为了向你们贩买冰毒
Is to sell you meth.
你们对我而言  只是顾客
You're nothing to me but customers!
你们中了我的圈套
I made you my bitch.
这你也接受吗
You okay with that?
你接受吗
You accept?
不
No.
我该走了
About time.
杰西  杰西
Jesse. Jesse.
把手电拿过来  好吗
Bring that light over here, will you?
你看见那儿有残渣吗
You see any residue there?
哪儿
Where?
在这儿  底下  就在那儿
Here. On the bottom, right-- right there.
已经一周了
It's been a week.
进展如何
What's going on?
我还没见到他
I haven't seen him.
我想不是
I didn't think so,
不过我会再清洁一遍
but I'll just give it another shot anyway.
伙计
Hey-hey-hey, buddy!
瞧瞧  当上门卫了
Look at that. Graduated to doorman.
终于收到你的来电
Finally found your calling.
瞧那小胡子  玛丽
Ha ha! Ooh! Little whiskers, Marie.
怎么了  你给理发师看了狗屁股照
What did you do, show your barber a picture of a dog's ass
然后说"就照这个剪"
and said "I'll take that"?
你还是那么逗  欢迎回来
Charming as usual. Welcome back.
气色不错  玛丽
Looking good, Marie.
谢了  史蒂芬  很高兴见到你
Oh, thanks, Steve. Good to see you.
-你好吗  -他很好
- How you doing? - He's doing fine.
你可以回去了
We, uh, we can take it from here.
-是吧  戈麦斯  -是
- Right, Gomie? - Yeah.
你能挽着他吗
If you want to hold his elbow.
不不不  把你的手拿开
No, no, no, no. You keep your mitts off me.
我没事  我没事
I'm good, I'm good.
祝你好运
Good luck.
走吧  迟到了  快
Let's go. Running late. Come on.
汉克  看着你走进这里
Hank, seeing you walk in here.
我真是无法表达这对我们所有人的意义
I can't tell you what that means to all of us.
你的进步真是惊人
Your progress, it's incredible.
是啊  多谢安静的生活和那些维生素片
Yeah, well, chalk it up to clean living and vitamin pills.
史蒂芬告诉你他的好消息了吗
Steve tell you his news?
什么事  终于来月经了吗
What? Finally got your period?
我晋升到14级了
I made GS 14.
美国联邦政府职员总表共分15级  13至15级为最高级
不错啊  兄弟
Wow. That's all right, man.
下一站就是华府
Next stop, Washington, D.C.,
坐在写字桌后面
sitting behind a desk,
文件堆积如山  视线全被遮住
papers piled so high, you can't see over them.
你混的比我好  兄弟
Hey, better you than me, buddy.
说真的  恭喜你  兄弟
Seriously, congratulations, buddy.
谢谢
Thanks.
史蒂芬说你有线索提供给我们
Steve said you might have something for us.
算是吧
Yeah, maybe.
这得你们说了算
You guys are going to have to tell me.
还记得提姆・罗伯茨吗
Remember my pal Tim Roberts?
阿尔布开克警局的探员吗
APD detective?
对  他在调查一宗凶案
Yeah, well, he's working on a murder case,
死者是一个34岁的男性白人
and the victim's a 34-year-old male Caucasian
名叫盖尔・伯蒂彻
by the name of Gale Boetticher.
上个月的一个晚上  伯蒂彻打开门
One night last month, Boetticher opens the door--
脸上就吃了颗子弹
bam, take a bullet to the face
凶手是一个人  也可能好几个
from a person or persons unknown.
盖尔・伯蒂彻绝对是个化学奇才
Now, this Gale Boetticher is a bona fide chemistry genius.
他的学位多的是  是吧
I mean, he's got degrees up the wazoo, right?
而且  你们可能会想  他是个正宗的书呆子
And, uh, as you might expect, he's a nerd's nerd.
素食主义者  不拘小节的那种人
Vegan, sandals and socks kind of guy.
结果是  他还是个头号制毒师
As it turns out, he's also an A-number 1 meth cook.
而引起我注意的
And what caught my eye
是  他的特色产品是蓝色冰毒
is, uh, his specialty product's blue.
你怎么看
So what are you thinking?
他就是海森堡
This is your Heisenberg?
不  我觉得他是
No. What I think we got here is, uh, ahem,
海森堡的前任毒师
Heisenberg's former cook
也可能是海森堡自己的一个环节
and maybe a line on Heisenberg himself.
不管怎样  你们瞧
Anyway, uh, lo and behold,
在那么多有的没的当中
amidst all the hippie-dippie nonsense, ahem,
我发现了这个
I find this.
这里  我在网上进行了搜索
Now, this here I do a little Google-fu,
然后我发现这是个零件编码
and I-- I realize it's a parts number
是这宝贝特有的
specifically for this baby.
这是个大容量的
Now, that there is a high-volume
高效空气过滤器  工业用空气过滤系统
HEPA industrial air filtration system.
那是个价值三十万的小配件
That's a $300,000 gadget.
非常适合用于制药厂
Be perfect for a pharmaceutical plant
或微芯制造厂
or microchip factory
也可以是边境北部最大的病毒实验室
or maybe the biggest meth lab north of the border.
好吧
Okay.
所以这个小玩意儿
So this little dingus here is manufactured
是一个大型国际公司制造的
by a big international concern--
叫牧歌电气
Madrigal Electromotive.
我致电了他们休斯顿办公室  然后接通了
I call their Houston office, and eventually I get through
他们最热心的20岁的临时工
to the nicest little 20-year-old temp.
我说了点好话
I use some of the Schrader sweet talk on her.
很快  她就给我查资料了
Before you know it, she's pulling files for me.
结果查到六个月前
Turns out six months ago,
这些系统中有一个被运送到
one of these systems was shipped to a depot
阿尔布开克州一个仓库
right here in ABQ.
谁签收的
Who signed for it?
盖尔・伯蒂彻
Gale Boetticher.
于是我就问这位新女朋友  是谁付的钱
So I asked my new girlfriend who paid for it,
她回答"没人"
and she says "Nobody."
他们没有付款人记录
They have no record that anybody actually paid for this thing.
所以我又回去让她多提供点线索  很快
So I go back and push more, and before you know it,
这个临时工走了  也查不到转递地址
uh, the temp's gone, there's no forwarding address,
然后我就和一个蛮横的公司律师说话了
and I'm talking to some snot-nose corporate lawyer
他还要了我的徽章号
who's asking me for my badge number.
此路不通
Brick wall.
所以我查了查牧歌电气
So I take a peek into Madrigal Electromotive.
现在牧歌总部在德国汉诺威
Now, Madrigal is based in Hanover, Germany,
可他们自称是非常多样化的
but they're what they call highly diversified--
涉足工业设备  全球运输
industrial equipment, global shipping,
重大建筑项目
major construction,
还在美国快餐业占有一席之地
and a tiny little foothold in American fast food,
尤其是当地的连锁店
specifically a local chain--
洛博罗炸鸡馆
Pollos Hermanos.
好  那又怎样  对吧  伯蒂彻死了
Okay. So what, right? Boetticher's dead.
我没有他资助人的线索
I got no line on who's been bankrolling him
也不知道他的实验室地址
or where his lab was.
整件事都没个头绪  对吧
The whole thing's a snipe hunt, right?
但现在我有个大胆的想法
But now I get this crazy idea,
而我挥之不去
and I can't shake it.
我整晚盯着天花板
I mean, I-- I stay up nights staring at the ceiling
想理清头绪
and trying to make sense of it.
是那张餐巾纸
It's that napkin.
记得我说过伯蒂彻是素食主义者吧
Remember I told you Boetticher's vegan, right?
我们还讨论过这家伙自己做扁豆面包
I mean, we're talking this guy makes his own fermented lentil bread
管它是什么
or whatever the hell that is.
一个素食主义者去炸鸡店干什么
What's a vegan doing in a fried chicken joint?
或许是去见人
Maybe he's meeting somebody.
谁呢
Like who?
比如...
Well, like maybe...
这个人
this guy.
我们对古斯塔沃・福林了解多少
I mean, what do we know about Gustavo Fring?
这个"执法部门的朋友"
Huh? This whole "Friend of law enforcement" Thing, eh,
可以让你和朋友亲近
could be a case of keep your friends close
可也能拉近与敌人的关系
but your enemies closer.
他花钱负担这次行动
He's got the money to finance this operation.
也许他也脱不了干系
Maybe he's got the connections, too.
也许  只是也许
Maybe, just maybe...
他就是我们要找的人
he's our guy.
汉克  恕我冒犯
Hank, no offense,
可我觉得你有些过头了
but I think you're really reaching.
如果这个人约了人在肯德基
If your guy had his meeting at KFC,
你不会立马想到
you wouldn't immediately assume
他的资助人是肯德基爷爷吧
that he's sitting down with Colonel Sanders.
我...
You know, I-- ahem--
我非常同意你们的观点
I couldn't agree more, guys.
古斯塔沃・福林  蓝色冰毒
Gustavo Fring, blue meth, you know...
这整件事都太离谱了
The whole thing is off-the-map nuts.
我真该戴上锡纸帽
I ought to be wearing a tinfoil hat, you know?
除非
Except...
我无法用这个小东西包上脑袋
I can't seem to wrap my mind around this one little thing,
这图上是
and that is...
为什么古斯塔沃・福林的指纹
what are Gustavo Fring's fingerprints...
出现在盖尔・伯蒂彻的公寓里
doing in Gale Boetticher's apartment?